Guide to the H.D. Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1918-77; Series II; 11; (27 boxes)
  - POETRY
    - Hermetic Definition
      - First draft, corrected by H.D.
        - "Sagesse," typescript, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 889)
        - "Sagesse," typescript, carbon, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 890)
        - "Winterlove," typescript, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 891)
        - "Winterlove," typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 892)
      - Second draft
        - Typescript, corrected by H.D., 1961 (Box 34, Folder 893)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1960 (Box 34, Folder 894)
        - "Winterlove," carbon, corrected H.D., 1959 (Box 34, Folder 895-96)
        - "Sagesse," typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1957-58 (Box 34, Folder 897)
      - Third draft, typescript, photocopy, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 898)
      - Final draft: "Sagesse"
        - "The Shell:" printed version
          See: Related Papers, Box 63, folders 1433
      - Source material, 1960-73 (Box 34, Folder 899)
    - Hippolytus Temporizes
      - Selections, typescript, 1962-63 (Box 34, Folder 900)
    - "Hymen"
      - Selections, typescript, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 901)
      - Reviews, 1922 (Box 34, Folder 902)
    - "Hymn"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 903)
    - "I Said"
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., 1919 (Box 34, Folder 904)
    - "Leda"
      - Printed version
        See: Related Papers, Box 63, folder 1434
    - "The Master"
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 905)
    - "Orestes Theme"
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 906)
    - "Other Sea-Cities"
      - Typescript, with carbon, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 907)
    - Palimpsest
      - Verse selection, holograph, 1926 (Box 34, Folder 908)
      - Verse selection, typescript, 1926 (Box 34, Folder 909)
      - Reviews, 1926-27 (Box 34, Folder 910)
    - Poems (early) [I]
      - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1917 (Box 34, Folder 911)
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected by Norman Holmes Pearson, 1917 (Box 34, Folder 912)
    - Poems (early) [II]
      - Holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 913)
    - Poems (early) [III]
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 35, Folder 914)
    - Poems (early) [IV]
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 35, Folder 915)
    - Poems (early) [V]
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 35, Folder 916)
    - "The Poet"
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 35, Folder 917)
    - Red Roses for Bronze
      - Selections, typescript, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 918)
      - Reviews, 1931-32 (Box 35, Folder 919)
    - Selected Poems of H.D.
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D. and Norman Holmes Pearson, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 920)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected by Norman Holmes Pearson, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 921)
      - Notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 922)
      - Galley proofs, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 923)
      - Reviews, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 924)
    - "Scribe"
      - Typescript, with carbons, ca. 1952 (Box 35, Folder 925)
    - "Sea Garden"
      - Selections, typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 35, Folder 926)
    - "The Shepherd"
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 35, Folder 927)
    - "Temple of the Sun"
      - Fragments, typescript, ca. 1939 (Box 35, Folder 928)
    - "To H. C. T. D."
      - Typescript, carbon, 1945 (Box 35, Folder 929)
    - Tribute to the Angels
      - Galley proofs, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 930)
        See also: Related Papers, Box 63, folder 1436
      - Page proofs, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 931)
      - Reviews, 1945, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 932)
    - "Two Poems"
      - "Choragus" and "Helen:" printed
        version
        See: Related Papers, Box 63, folder 1435
    - Vale Ave
      - Notebooks, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 933)
      - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1957 (Box 36, Folder 934)
      - Second draft, typescript, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 935)
      - Second draft, typescript, carbon, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 936)
      - Third draft, typescript, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 937)
      - Third draft, typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1957 (Box 36, Folder 938)
      - Third draft, typescript, photocopy, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 939)
      - Fourth draft, typescript, corrected by Norman Holmes Pearson, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 940)
      - Fifth draft, typescript, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 941)
      - Selections, typescript, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 942)
    - The Walls Do Not Fall
      - Selections, typescript, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 943)
      - Page proofs, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 944)
      - Reviews, 1944, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 945)
    - What Do I Love
      - "Christmas 1944"
        - First draft, typescript, [1944] (Box 36, Folder 946)
        - Second draft, typescript, with photocopies, [1944] (Box 36, Folder 947)
      - "May 1943"
        - First draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 948)
        - Second draft, typescript, [1943] (Box 36, Folder 949)
      - "R. A. F."
        - First draft, typescript, 1941 (Box 36, Folder 950)
        - Second draft, typescript, 1941 (Box 36, Folder 951)
  - SHORT STORIES
    - [Early Stories I]
      - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 37, Folder 952)
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected by Norman Holmes Pearson (Box 37, Folder 953)
    - [Early Stories II]
      - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 37, Folder 954)
      - Second draft, corrected by Norman Holmes Pearson (Box 37, Folder 955)
    - Ear-ring
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 37, Folder 956)
      - Proofs, 1936 (Box 37, Folder 957)
      - Printed version, 1932 (Box 37, Folder 958)
    - The Moment [Seven Stories]
      - "Aegina"
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1924-34 (Box 37, Folder 959)
        - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1933 (Box 37, Folder 960)
        - Third draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1933 (Box 37, Folder 961)
        - Fourth draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 962)
      - "The Death of Martin Dresser"
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1943 (Box 37, Folder 963)
        - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1943 (Box 37, Folder 964)
      - "The Guardians"
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1945 (Box 37, Folder 965)
        - Second draft, typescript, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 966)
        - Second draft, typescript, carbon, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 967)
      - "Hysperia"
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1924-48 (Box 37, Folder 968)
        - Second draft, corrected by H.D., 1924-48 (Box 37, Folder 969-70)
        - Third draft, typescript, 1924-48 (Box 37, Folder 971)
      - "Jubilee"
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1935 (Box 37, Folder 972)
        - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1935 (Box 37, Folder 973)
        - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1935 (Box 37, Folder 974)
      - "The Last Time"
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1936 (Box 37, Folder 975)
        - Second draft, typescript, [1936] (Box 37, Folder 976)
        - Second draft, typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1936 (Box 37, Folder 977)
      - "The Moment"
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1926 (Box 37, Folder 978)
        - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1926 (Box 38, Folder 979)
        - Second draft, typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1926 (Box 38, Folder 980)
    - "Pontokonisi (Mouse Island)"
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., 1937 (Box 38, Folder 981)
      - Printed version, 1932 (Box 38, Folder 982)
    - Within the Walls
      - "Within the Walls"
        - Typescript, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 983)
        - Typescript, carbon, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 984)
      - "Bunny"
        - Typescript, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 985)
        - Typescript, carbon, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 986)
      - "Pattern"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 987)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 988)
      - "Dream of a Book"
        - Typescript, corrected, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 989)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 990)
      - "Escape"
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 991-92)
      - "Blue Lights"
        - Typescript, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 993)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 994)
      - "Tide-line"
        - Typescript, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 995)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 996)
      - "Warehouse"
        - Typescript, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 997)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 998)
      - "The Last Day"
        - Typescript, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 999)
        - Typescript, carbon, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 1000)
      - "Nefert"
        - Typescript, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 1001)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 1002)
      - "She is Dead"
        - Typescript, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 1003)
        - Typescript, carbon, 1941 (Box 38, Folder 1004)
      - "Saint Anthony"
        - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1005)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1006)
      - "The Ghost"
        - Typescript, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 1007)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1941 (Box 38, Folder 1008)
      - "Before the Battle"
        - Typescript, corrected by H.D., 1940 (Box 38, Folder 1009)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1940 (Box 38, Folder 1010)
  - AUTOBIOGRAPHICAL WRITINGS
    - Compassionate Friendship
      - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1955 (Box 38, Folder 1011)
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1955 (Box 38, Folder 1012)
      - Second draft, carbon, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 1013)
      - Notes, 1955 (Box 38, Folder 1014)
    - End to Torment
      - Parts I-IV, notebooks, ca. 1958 (Box 38, Folder 1015-16)
      - Parts I-IV, notebooks, photocopy, ca. 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1017-18)
      - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1019-20)
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1021)
      - Third draft, typescript, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1022-23)
      - Third draft, typescript, corrected, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1024)
      - Fourth draft, typescript, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1025)
      - Fourth draft, typescript, photocopy, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1026)
      - Fifth draft, typescript, annotated by Norman Holmes Pearson, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1027)
    - The Gift
      - [Part I-VI], first draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1028-33)
      - [Part VII], first draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1034)
      - Part I-VII, first draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1941-42 (Box 40, Folder 1035-38)
      - Notes, first draft, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1039)
      - Part I-VII, second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D. (Box 40, Folder 1040-42)
      - Notes, second draft (Box 40, Folder 1043)
      - Part I-VII, third draft, typescript, 1941-43 (Box 40, Folder 1044-47)
      - Notes, third draft, typescript, 1940-41 (Box 40, Folder 1048-49)
      - Part I-II, third draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1050)
      - Part III-VII, third draft, photocopy, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1051-53)
    - [ Thorn Thicket ]
      - "Bosquet"
        - Notebook, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 1054)
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1960 (Box 41, Folder 1055)
        - First draft, typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1960 (Box 41, Folder 1056)
        - Second draft, typescript, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 1057)
        - Second draft, typescript, carbon, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 1058)
    - Tribute to Freud
      - "Advent"
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1948 (Box 41, Folder 1059)
        - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1948 (Box 41, Folder 1060)
        - Second draft, carbon, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1948 (Box 41, Folder 1061)
        - Second draft, typescript, corrected by Norman Holmes Pearson, photocopy, 1948 (Box 41, Folder 1062)
        - Third draft, typescript, p. 86-173, ca. 1948 (Box 41, Folder 1063)
        - Third draft, typescript, p. 86-173, photocopy, ca. 1974 (Box 41, Folder 1064)
      - "Writing on the Wall"
        - Notebook, 1944 (Box 42, Folder 1065)
        - Foreword to the first edition, first draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1066)
        - Foreword to the first edition, second draft, typescript (Box 42, Folder 1067)
        - Foreword to the first edition, second draft, typescript, carbon (Box 42, Folder 1068)
        - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1944 (Box 42, Folder 1069-70)
        - Second draft, setting typescript (Box 42, Folder 1071-72)
        - Printed version: "Écrit sur le mur." [French translation]
          See: Related Papers, Box 63, folder 1437
      - Dustjacket and draft of jacket blurb (Box 42, Folder 1073)
      - Detached pages from Life and Letters Today, 1945-46 (Box 42, Folder 1074)
      - Reviews, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 1075)
  - MISCELLANEOUS WRITINGS
    - Borderline: page proofs, corrected by H.D., 1930 (Box 42, Folder 1076)
    - Choruses from the Iphigeneia in Aulis and the Hippolytus of Euripides: reviews, 1919 (Box 42, Folder 1077)
    - Close Up contributions
      - "Art and the Screen, the Stranglehold of Mediocrity," typescript (Box 42, Folder 1078)
      - "Boo"
        - Proofs, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1079)
        - Proofs, photocopies, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1080)
      - "The Cinema and the Classics. Beauty"
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1081)
        - Proofs, first state, photocopy, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1082-83)
        - Proofs, second state (Box 42, Folder 1084)
        - Proofs, second state, photocopy (Box 42, Folder 1085)
        - Proofs, third state, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1086)
      - "The Cinema and the Classics. Restraint"
        - Typescript, corrected, 1928 (Box 42, Folder 1087)
        - Proofs, with photocopies, 1928 (Box 42, Folder 1088)
      - "The Cinema and the Classics. The Mask and the Movietones," proofs, corrected by H.D. (Box 42, Folder 1089)
      - "Conrad Veidt," proofs, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1090)
      - "Expiation"
        - Proofs, first state, corrected, 1928 (Box 42, Folder 1091)
        - Proofs, second state, 1928 (Box 42, Folder 1092)
      - "Joan of Arc"
        - Typescript, corrected by H.D., 1928 (Box 43, Folder 1093)
        - Proofs, corrected, 1928 (Box 43, Folder 1094)
      - "The King of Kings Again"
        - Proofs, first state, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1095)
        - Proofs, second state (Box 43, Folder 1096)
      - "Projector" [verse]
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1097)
        - Proofs, first state, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1098)
        - Proofs, second state (Box 43, Folder 1099)
      - "Projector II" [verse]
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1100)
        - Proofs, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1101)
      - "Wingbeat," typescript, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1102)
    - "Dante and his Circle," notes, 1948 (Box 43, Folder 1103)
    - "The Griffin of the Temple Bar," printed version
      See: Oversize, Box 62, folder 1430a
    - "H.D. by Delia Alton"
      See: Notes on recent writing, Box 44, folders 1121-25
    - "The Hedgehog" [children's book]
      - Specimen page, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 1104)
      - Reviews, 1936-37 (Box 43, Folder 1105)
    - Hirslanden [Journal], holograph, 1957-60 (Box 43, Folder 1106-09)
    - Introduction to work by Kenneth Macpherson, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1110)
    - "Lady Leister," printed version [2 copies]
      See: Oversize, Box 62, folder 1430b
    - "A Letter from England," printed version
      See: Related Papers, Box 63, folder 1438
    - Notes on Dorothy Richardson and Alan Odle (Box 43, Folder 1111)
    - Notes on Euripides, Pausanius, and Greek Lyric Poets
      - Fragments of Sappho, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1112)
      - People of Sparta, typescript, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1113)
      - People of Sparta, and Those Near the Sea, holograph, 1920 (Box 43, Folder 1114)
      - Part I, first draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1918-20 (Box 43, Folder 1115)
      - Part I, first draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1918-20 (Box 43, Folder 1116)
      - Part II-III, first draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1918-20 (Box 43, Folder 1117)
      - Part II-III, first draft, typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1118)
      - Part I-III, second draft, typescript, corrected by Norman Holmes Pearson (Box 44, Folder 1119-20)
    - Notes on recent writing
      - First draft, typescript, 1950 (Box 44, Folder 1121)
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1949-50 (Box 44, Folder 1122)
      - Third draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., 1949 (Box 44, Folder 1123)
      - Third draft, typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1949 (Box 44, Folder 1124)
      - Fourth draft, typescript, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 1125)
    - Notes on thought and vision
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D. (Box 44, Folder 1126)
      - Third draft, typescript, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 1127)
      - Third draft, typescript, carbon, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 1128)
      - Fourth draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1129)
      - Fourth draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1130)
    - Prose Chorus
      - Printed version
        See: Related Papers, Box 63, folder 1439
    - Prose Corybantic
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1131)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1132)
      - Detached copy of sections, published in Blues, 1929 (Box 44, Folder 1133)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Aldington, Catherine
      - [Poems], typescript, 1960, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1134)
    - Aldington, Richard
      - [ The Love of Myrrhine and Konalis ] selections, typescript (Box 45, Folder 1135)
      - [Poems], typescript, 1929-59 (Box 45, Folder 1136)
      - "Prayers and Fantasies," holograph, 1918 (Box 45, Folder 1137)
    - Ashby, Elizabeth
      - In the Sierra de Ronda, watercolor (Box 45, Folder 1138)
    - Blunden, Edmund
      - [Poems], typescript, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1139)
    - Bryher
      - "Along the River," typescript, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 1140)
      - "The Powers of Ancient Egypt," notes, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1141)
      - "Young Rawley," typescript, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1142)
    - Cunard, Nancy
      - Black Man and White Ladyship: An Anniversary, 1931 (Box 45, Folder 1143)
    - Duncan, Robert
      - [Poems], typescript, 1960 (Box 45, Folder 1144)
      - "Toward a Study of H.D.," typescript, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1145)
    - Eastwood, Thomas
      - "At Baia" by H.D., music by Thomas Eastwood, holograph
        See: Oversize, Box 62, folder 1430c
    - Elkus, Jonathan
      - "Triptych" by H.D., music by Jonathan Elkus, holograph, photocopy
        See: Oversize, Box 62, folder 1430d
    - Herring, Robert
      - "Elegy on a Ghost Passing Beyond Knowledge of her own Ghostliness", typescript (Box 45, Folder 1146)
      - ["The Fourth Mary"], typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1147)
      - ["The Fourth Mary"], notes, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1148)
      - "Love Song of Penance Impenitent", typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1149)
      - "The Sole Sentinel or Harlequin in Perspective", typescript, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1150)
      - "The True History of the Life and Death of the Valorous Colonel, typescript, carbon (Box 45, Folder 1151)
    - Hesse, Hermann
      - A-Z, miscellaneous, 1947-57 (Box 45, Folder 1152-53)
      - [Poems], 1954-58 (Box 45, Folder 1154)
    - Levertov, Denise
      - [Poems], holograph, and typescript, 1959-60 (Box 45, Folder 1155)
    - Nagy, Niclas Christoph de
      - Amerikas bahnbrechende Dichterin in Unserer Zeit, typescript, photocopy, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 1156)
    - Paolini, Robert W.
      - Never More the Wind, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 1157)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes
      - "Billy Budd: The King's Yarn:"
        See: Box 63, folder 1440
      - The American Poet in Relation to Science, typescript, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1158)
    - Reiniger, Lotte
      - "Birthday Prayer for H.D.," holograph, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1159)
    - Sarton, May
      - "Those Images Remain," typescript, 1949 (Box 46, Folder 1160)
    - Schaffner, Perdita
      - Untitled autobiographical manuscript, typescript, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1161-65)
    - Sitwell, Edith
      - "The Bee Keeper," typescript, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1166)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr
      - "In the Night," holograph, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1167)
    - Urzidil, Johannes
      - Amerika und die Antike, 1960 (Box 46, Folder 1168)
    - White, Eric Walter (Box 46, Folder 1169)
      "Early Theatrical Performances of Purcell's Operas," printed version,
      See: Related Papers, Box 63, folder 1441
      - [Poems], holograph, typescript, and printed, 1960, n.d.
      - "A Song from Cyprus," and "Three Songs from Cyprus," musical setting, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 1170)
    - Williams, William Carlos
      - [Review of] Collected Poems of H.D., typescript, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1171)
    - Yudkin, Michael
      - "Sea Rose," musical setting, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1172)
- Personal Papers, 1911-63; Series III; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series III houses Personal Papers. The material is arranged alphabetically by type and includes financial papers, medical records, and genealogical papers.
  - Acceptance speech: American Academy of Arts and Letters (Box 47, Folder 1173)
  - Address books, 1946-59 (Box 47, Folder 1174)
  - Artwork, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1175)
  - Astrology
    - Horoscopes, miscellaneous, 1953-59 (Box 47, Folder 1176-78)
    - Horoscope, Erich Heydt, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1179)
    - Notes, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 1180)
  - Autobiographical notes, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1181-82)
  - Awards
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1959-60 (Box 47, Folder 1183)
    - Brandeis University Creative Arts Award, 1959 (Box 47, Folder 1184)
    - Bryn Mawr College, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 1185)
    - Harriet Monroe Prize, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 1186)
  - Biographical information, 1934-61, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1187-88)
  - Birth certificates
    - H.D., 1938, 1961 (Box 47, Folder 1189)
    - Perdita Schaffner, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 1190)
  - Bookplates, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1191)
  - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1192)
  - Candle lists, 1958, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1193)
  - Criticism and interpretation, 1933-63 (Box 47, Folder 1194)
  - Commission: Richard Aldington, 1917 (Box 47, Folder 1195)
  - Diary, 1911-12 (Box 47, Folder 1196)
  - Diary, 1955-59 (Box 48, Folder 1197-99)
  - Diary, 1961 (Box 48, Folder 1200)
  - Divorce, 1937-38 (Box 48, Folder 1201)
  - Doolittle, Helen Wolle
    - Diaries, 1911-24 (Box 48, Folder 1202-03)
    - Estate, 1921-27 (Box 48, Folder 1204)
  - Estate, 1955-62 (Box 48, Folder 1205)
  - Financial Papers
    - Bank books, 1918-27 (Box 48, Folder 1206)
    - Contracts: Chatto and Windus, 1931-36 (Box 48, Folder 1207)
    - Contracts: Houghton-Mifflin, 1928-36 (Box 48, Folder 1208)
    - Contracts: Macmillan and Company, 1948 (Box 48, Folder 1209)
    - Contracts: Oxford University Press, 1943-44 (Box 48, Folder 1210)
    - Invoices and receipts, 1938-56 (Box 48, Folder 1211)
    - Royalty statements: Chatto and Windus, 1931-36 (Box 48, Folder 1212)
    - Royalty statements: Faber and Faber, 1936 (Box 48, Folder 1213)
    - Royalty statements: Henry Holt and Company, 1924 (Box 48, Folder 1214)
    - Royalty statements: Houghton Mifflin Company, 1925-49 (Box 48, Folder 1215)
    - Royalty statements: Liveright, 1945-51 (Box 48, Folder 1216)